<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dale Richardson</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dale Richardson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays and Happiness - What makes a country happy?</title>
      <link>/post/holidays_happiness/holidays-and-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/holidays_happiness/holidays-and-happiness/</guid>
      <description>Description Over the past year I have spent a good portion of time in the office studying and preparing for a career transition. Finding a suitable work-life balance has been difficult, especially with the clock ticking on my post-doctoral fellowship running out in December, 2017. Most free moments I have during the day are usually d towards studying something datascience related or doing some sports in an effort to keep mind and body balanced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting housing prices in Ames, Iowa - Captsone Project for Coursera Statistics with R Specialization</title>
      <link>/projects/duke_capstone/predicting-housing-prices-in-ames-iowa-captsone-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/duke_capstone/predicting-housing-prices-in-ames-iowa-captsone-project/</guid>
      <description>Description Part 1 - Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) Exploratory Data Analysis  Part 2 - Development and assessment of an initial model, following a semi-guided process of analysis Section 2.1 An Initial Model Section 2.2 Model Selection Section 2.3 Initial Model Residuals Section 2.4 Initial Model RMSE Section 2.5 Overfitting  Part 3 Development of a Final Model Section 3.1 Final Model Section 3.2 Transformation Section 3.3 Variable Interaction Section 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>Dale Richardson, PhD I am a bioinformatics analyst of large scale genomics data and aspiring data scientist with an intense dedication to continued learning.
Scientific research interests Post-transcriptional gene regulation, alternative splicing, comparative genomics, abiotic stress response
Currently I conduct research on alternative splicing and abiotic stress responses in the model plant, Arabidopsis thaliana. In my spare time, I take online courses in preparation for a career transition into data analysis/data science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Dale</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Currently I&amp;rsquo;m a postdoc in the Plant Molecular Biology Laboratory at the Instituto Gulbenkian de Ciência (IGC), a research institution located just outside of Lisbon, Portugal. I primarily rely on R and a suite of bioinformatics tools to analyze large-scale genomic changes in response to abiotic stress in the model plant organism, Arabidopsis thaliana, commonly known as the &amp;ldquo;thale cress&amp;rdquo;.
In transition Although I hold a special place in my heart for research science, it has become abundantly clear to me that I need to move into a new challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>